Wearing a long-tattered gown,
I went straight to the pub in Lu Town.
I called the waiter and ordered two bowls of wine
and a plate of fennel beans for 9 coins.
I spoke in a Classical Chinese style (obscure or complicated language to sound intelligent), which drew ridicule.
Unconsciously, my face turned red.
How can you tarnish my innocence like this?
I took a sip of wine and continued to argue with them.
The reason why Xiangzi (from Rickshaw Boy) died
was because he did not work hard enough to pull his rickshaw.
In every article by Lu Xun,
he touches upon the untouchable topics.
Chen Sheng and Wu Guang did not have sweet lives (first uprising against the Qin dynasty)
because they did not have their feet on the ground (being realistic).
At the last moment, everyone in the pub turned their eyes toward me,
asking what kind of thing did I become.
I looked at my long gown and said that I was
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
In his bizarre writing style, he questioned if I was convinced or not.
Even if my labor falls into the river, I won't sell myself cheaply to you.
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
You drive a Lamborghini but laugh at me for not working hard enough.
What does this decaying old society have to do with me?
Although I wash my face every day,
my empty pockets are cleaner than my face.
I have to wear a changshan (traditional Manchu robe),
and work hard copying books for the officials.
I thought the job would be easy,
but it turned out to be 996 (from 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM, 6 days per week).
After finishing my work, I maliciously demanded my wages,
and the hungry me was arrested by the officials.
Why does this extremely evil old society
have no labor laws?
Why is the dignity of us common people
so easily trampled by the meat eaters?
These outrageous stories and experiences of suffering,
no one dares to answer them now.
Finally, the diners turned their eyes toward me,
asking why was I not afraid at all.
I smiled and said because I am
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
The small and weak branches have already given up struggling long ago.
The edges and corners wore away over time, leaving only a few scars.
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
Optimism is my claws and teeth, while tears flow behind my mask.
When you ask me if I am happy, I just want to curse.
After I finished speaking,
the air in the pub was filled with joy.
What do those insults, doubts, refutations, and ridicule
have to do with me?
Studying is for the rise of China,
not for delivering takeout or packages.
After everyone listened, they all showed a candid smile,
except for that idiot
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
Tear down this decaying wall, and seek the light of righteousness.
Regardless of criticism or praise, there needs to be someone applauding.
A sunny and cheerful Kong Yiji.
From all the top comments, how much hot blood is hard to cool down?
Kong Ming (Zhuge Liang, most accomplished strategist during the Three Kingdoms period) is my ideal, yet Shang Yang (minister of Qin, executed for treason by dismemberment) is my fate.